

ABOUT ME

Hello! I am Abdullah Ameen and currently I am looking for a job in the GIS/Civil Engineering field.

Recently I graduated with my master degree in GIS and Cartography from the University of Wisconsin – Madison (May 2020)

In 2001, I graduated with my bachelor's degree in Civil engineering from Kabul University – Afghanistan.

During my junior and senior years at the university I taught mathematics courses to high school students, which I enjoyed greatly.

I am a civil engineer by profession and have over 12 years of experience in Community Development/Subnational Governance, Project Management, Water Supply networks design, GIS Analysis, Education and Social Services.

Besides being a Civil Engineer, I am Cartographer, GIS Analyst, Graphic Designer, Mathematics Teacher, Front-End Developer and finally a Lifelong Learner.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Pashto Native
- Persian/Dari Native
- English Proficient
- Hindi/Urdu Intermediate

ABDULLAH AMEEN

Madison, Wisconsin 53704 | Cell: (608) 609 2098 | Email: abdullah.ameenn@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

- A multilingual professional fluent in English, Pashto, Dari/Persian, and basic Arabic.
- A cartographer, civil engineer and educator with over 12 years of diverse experiences.
- A detail oriented, hardworking, problem solver, patience and well-organized professional.
- Very good in coordination, self-management and good work ethics with public and staff.
- Very good in spatial data analysis, visualization, presentation and web mapping.

COMPUTER SKILLS

ArcGIS/QGIS	
MS Office	
HTML	
CSS	
Illustrator	
Auto CAD	
Photoshop	
Python	
JavaScript	
R	

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN MADISON - JAN 2017 - MAY 2020

MASTER IN GIS AND CARTOGRAPHY

University of Kabul Afghanistan – Mar 1997 – Dec 2001

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN CIVIL ENGINEERING

Link to my project portfolio: https://abdullahameen.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIS Intern

Telephone and Data Systems (TDS) | Oct 2019 - Present

- Adding easements and the Right of Way permits to databases.
- Transferring vendors details into ArcGIS Online and making vendors maps.
- Making traffic control plans, Exhibits and ESRI shapefiles for permit authorities
- Exporting permit details from Access database to ArcMap and ArcGIS Online.

Math/Science Instructor

Forward Service Corporation | May 2018 - Aug 2019

- Developed Upward Bound academic years curriculums.
- Took the students on a 5 weeks summer program to one of the public universities in Wisconsin.
- Conducted ACT prep training in Math and Science sections.
- Helped 60 students in math/science on regular basis.

Case Manager

Porchlight Inc. | Aug 2016 - Mar 2018

- Helped the clients to obtain stable housing and employment.
- Referred clients to available resources in the communities.
- Provided advocacy and case management to 10 permanent and 15 walks in clients.
- Assisted the clients maintain housing and employment.

Substitute Teacher/AVID Tutor

Madison School District | Sep 2015 - Feb 2018

- Provided classroom support to teachers and students.
- Facilitated tutorials sessions for students in math and science.
- As a substitute teacher managed a class of 25-30 students.

Program Support Unit Manager

AECOM International Development - SIKA-East | Feb 2012 - Sep 2014

- In coordination with other units, planned, budgeted and coordinated field activities for 21 districts and 6 provinces.
- Served as a liaison among the program stakeholders and the senior management of SIKA-East.
- Presented the program to the relevant institutions and to the public in the sub national level.
- Provided technical support to program and operations as needed.

Regional Manager

The Asia Foundation – Afghanistan - PBGF Program | Jan 2010 – Feb 2012

- Planned, budgeted, coordinated and evaluated the PBGF program for 4 provinces.
- Analyzed and presented the performance evaluation of provincial governors' offices in GIS.
- Assisted provincial governor offices with their quarterly and annual budgeting.
- Monitored budget's categories to make sure expenditures are in line with the program guideline.

Engineering Manager (Environmental)

International Rescue Committee (IRC) - National Solidarity Program | Mar 2005 - June 2009

- Supervised and leaded a group of 25 district engineers.
- Trained the district engineers in CAD, GIS, using of Garmin GPS and the design of water supply network.
- Checked technical accuracy of the sub project proposals before submission to donor.
- Contributed into establishment of more than 200 Community Development Councils (CDCs).

Design Engineer (Water Supply and Sanitation)

DACAAR - Pakistan & Afghanistan | June 2002 - Mar 2005

- Surveyed and designed water supply network projects, using GIS, MS Excel and EPANET.
- Provided technical support to the field teams during the project implementation.
- Inspected the quality of water before the survey of a project.